Corpsman!
看護兵！
For God sakes! Corpsman!
上帝啊！看護兵在哪？
Honey, what's wrong?
親愛的，怎麼了？
Every jackass thinks he knows what war is.
每個蠢蛋都自認為懂得戰爭
Especially those who've never been in one.
特別是那些從未踏入戰場的
We like things nice and simple,
我們總喜歡單純的事物
good and evil, heroes and villains.
善良與邪惡，英雄和惡棍
There's always plenty of both.
兩方面的例子都多得很
Most of the time, they are not who we think they are.
但多數時候 我們的想法和事實相去甚遠
Where is he?
他在哪？
Where... Where is he? Where is he?
他……他在哪？他在哪？
Mr. Bradley?
布萊德利先生？
Mr. B? You okay?
布萊德利先生？你還好吧？
- Where is he? - Where is who?
- 他在哪？ - 你說誰？
Where is he? Where did he go? Where... Where is he?
他在哪？他去哪了？ 他……他在哪？
All right. Just stay right here, okay?
呆著別動，好嗎？
I'm gonna call an ambulance. It'll be okay.
我馬上去叫救護車 不會有事的
Where is he?
他在哪？
Most guys I knew would never talk about what happened over there.
我所認識的人當中 大多數都閉口不提在那邊的經歷
Probably 'cause they're still trying to forget about it.
大概是因為他們依舊在試圖忘卻它
They certainly didn't think of themselves as heroes.
他們當然不認為自己是英雄
They died without glory.
沒有帶著榮耀去另一個世界
Nobody has taken their pictures.
也沒有留下照片
Only their buddies knew what they did.
只有他們的戰友知道他們的事跡
I'd tell their folks they died for their country.
我會告訴他們的家人 他們是為國捐軀的
I'm not sure that was it.
但我對此不是十分肯定
Now, there were plenty other photos taken that day,
那天其實還照了許多其它的照片
but none anybody wanted to see.
但除了那張，其它的沒有人關心
What we see and do in war,
戰爭中，我們親眼目睹和親身參與
the cruelty, is unbelievable.
那種殘酷是不可想像的
But somehow we gotta make some sense of it.
但是不管怎麼樣 我們總得讓它有些意義
To do that, we need a easy to understand truth
這樣的話 我們只需要一個淺顯的事實
and damn few words.
和三言兩語
Film's ruined.
膠片報廢了
I don't know. This one looks all right.
我不知道 但這張看起來沒事
And if you can get a picture...
如果你能得到一張照片……
Now, the right picture can win or lose a war.
好的照片可能會左右一場戰爭的勝負
You're gonna want to see this.
這個你肯定感興趣
Look at Vietnam.
想想越南吧
The picture of that South Vietnamese officer
那張南越軍官……
blowing that fella's brains out of the side of his head, whammo!
一槍讓那傢伙腦漿四濺的照片
That was it.
「崩」地一下，就完了
The war was lost.
戰爭就輸了
We just hung around trying to pretend it wasrt.
我們只不過賴在那裡不肯承認而已
Took a lot of other pictures that day. None of them made a difference.
那天照了很多其它的照片 但它們都大同小異
Thanks. Appreciate it.
多謝惠顧
Sounds ridiculous, but it happened.
聽起來很荒謬，但它確實發生了
Country was bankrupt.
當時國家瀕臨破產
People were becoming cynical and tired of war.
人們冷嘲熱諷，厭倦了戰爭
Oh, my Lord, that's Harlon!
噢，我的天，這不是哈龍嗎？
Where?
在哪？
Right there. Planting that flag, that's your brother.
這裡 正在插旗子的那個，是你哥哥
Ma, all you can see is his behind.
媽，你只能看到他的屁股
And that's his. I powdered and diapered it, I know my son.
就是他，我給他的屁股擦過粉換過尿布 我怎麼會不認識我兒子？
That's him. Go get your father.
就是他，快把你爸叫來
Daddy, Ma's got a picture of Harlors keister in the paper.
爸，媽這裡有一張報紙 印著哈龍的大屁屁
You watch your mouth, young man.
嘴巴乾淨點，小子
Thank you.
謝謝
One photo, almost all on its own, turned that around.
一張照片，幾乎獨力扭轉了局面
It's on the front page of every major paper.
每家大報的頭版都登著這張照片
Over 200 dailies and they're all flooded with requests for prints.
200多家日報社被讀者的信件淹沒 都是要求刊登這張照片的
I think we might have found it.
我們可能得把它找出來
Corpsman!
看護兵！
- I gotta go get him. - Oh, no, you don't.
- 我去找他 - 噢，不，別去
Iggy, I gotta go.
伊基，我得去
I have a whole different theory.
我的想法正相反
He wants medical attention bad enough, he'll come to us.
如果他真需要救護，他自己會過來的
Shut up and crawl over here, you lazy son-of-a-bitch!
別叫了，自己爬過來 你這個懶蟲！
As soon as that flare goes out.
照明彈一滅，我就衝過去
- Crap. Okay, well, I'll go with you. - No.
- 靠，好吧，我和你一起去 - 不用
You're actually gonna leave me here?
你其實是想把我丟在這裡？
I'll be right back, just shoot some people. I gotta go.
我馬上就回來 幫我掩護，我得去了
Oh, God.
噢，天
Okay, it's okay.
好，沒事的
Don't touch them. Don't touch them.
別碰傷口，別碰傷口
Get your hands out of there. Let me do that. I'll do it, okay?
把你手拿開 讓我來，我會搞定的，好嗎？
Don't look. Keep your head back. Keep your eyes on me.
別看，頭朝後仰 看著我
All right, look at me. I'll get it. I'll take care of it.
好，看著我 我會搞定的，我會處理好的
We'll get this bandage on you. We'll get you taken care of.
先用這個繃帶包紮一下 我們會好好照顧你的
And we'll get you down to the bottom, all right?
我們要把你抬到山下去，好嗎？
Look, you're gonna be fine.
瞧，你會沒事的
It's okay.
沒事的
I'll do that. I'll do that.
我來，我來
Here, put some pressure on that.
壓住這裡
Put your hands on top and put some pressure on it.
手放在上面壓住它
Keep your head back. Keep breathing.
頭朝後仰，保持呼吸節奏
Keep looking at me, all right? Just keep looking at...
看著我，好嗎？ 看著……
Doc.
大夫
Help me.
救救我
All right. Okay.
好吧
How's that feel?
感覺怎麼樣？
- It feels good. - It does? All right.
- 不錯 - 真的？好
- Good. - All right.
- 好
I'm gonna go get a stretcher and get you down to the beach. I'll be right back.
我去找個擔架，把你送到海灘上 我馬上就回來
I'm all right.
我沒事了
Go and help someone who's hurt.
去幫其他受傷的人吧
All right. Hold on there.
好，呆在這裡別動
- Where'd he go? - Who?
- 他去哪兒了？ - 誰？
The guy who was right here, Ignatowski. Where did he go?
在這裡的人，伊格納托斯基 他去哪兒了？
- I think you jumped in the wrong hole. - I didn't jump in the wrong hole!
- 我看你是進錯散兵坑了 - 我沒進錯！
He was right here, now where the hell is he?
剛才他還在這兒的 他到底去哪兒了？
Lggy!
伊基！
You shut up. You want every Jap on the island shooting at us?
別叫了，你想讓島上的鬼子 都朝我們這兒打嗎？
Lggy!
伊基！
Holy shit.
我的媽呀
They expect us to climb this?
他們想讓我們爬這個？
Or something just like it.
或者差不多的地方
So, where you think they're sending us?
你看他們會把我們送哪兒去？
I think it's the desert, Franklin.
我想是沙漠，富蘭克林
Well, that makes no sense at all.
那可沒道理
Well, it's just military psychology.
這叫軍事心理學
They always train you for the desert on a volcano.
為了適應沙漠 他們總是在火山上訓練你
Now you're just having fun with me.
你們在拿我開心
Harlon, take your men right.
哈龍，帶你的人去右邊
- Watch for Bedouins. - Yes, sir.
- 小心那些貝都因人* - 明白，長官 （*沙漠地帶從事遊牧的阿拉伯人）
- What's a Bedouin? - It's a guy with a camel.
- 貝都因人是什麼？ - 騎駱駝的人
Well, Jeez Louise, maybe we are going to the desert.
噢，上帝 我們可能真要去沙漠
Now, you tilt that to the right, but what if the bullet comes from the left?
你把它歪戴在右邊 如果有子彈從左邊飛來，怎麼辦？
Bullets don't come from the left. You know any left-handed Japs?
子彈不可能從左邊來 你認識左撇子的日本鬼子？
That makes about as much sense as you showering with your shoes on.
這就和你穿著鞋洗澡一樣 其實一點道理都沒有
You don't even know why you do it, do you?
你甚至不知道自己為什麼那麼戴 不是嗎？
'Cause I don't tell you mean I don't know?
我不告訴你就證明我不知道？
You do it 'cause Mike does it.
因為你只是學邁克而已
I'll ask him.
我會問他的
So you cut hair back home?
你在老家也幫人理發？
Some.
有時候
Training to be a barber, are you, Doc?
你想學當理髮師，是吧，大夫？
No, I just studied it a little.
不，我只是學了點皮毛
But not in barber school?
不是在理發學校學的？
Nope.
不是
- Gosh. - Let me guess, Hayes is winning.
- 唉 - 讓我猜一下，海耶斯贏了
Chief, I had very little to do with Sitting Bull's death,
酋長，我跟「坐牛」*的死沒有關係 （*北美印第安蘇族部落的酋長 曾在小大角溪之戰中大敗美軍）
so maybe you could stop taking it out on me.
你要報仇可別找我
Different tribe. The Pimas fought on the side of the white man.
搞錯部落了吧 我們皮瑪人*可是站在白人這邊的 （*北美印第安部落的一支 現在主要居住在美國亞利桑那州中部）
- See, now that's smart. - That is smart.
- 看，這就是聰明 - 這就是聰明
Yeah. Worked real good for us.
耶，確實不賴
Good luck, fellas.
好運，夥計們
Hey, good night, Lindberg.
嘿，晚安，林德伯格
Dead bodies. He cuts hair on dead bodies.
死人 他竟然給死人剃頭
What? Even I knew that.
怎麼了？我早就知道
- Who's in? - Oh, I'm in. I'm in.
- 誰來？ - 噢，我來，我來
It must be a lot easier with them not moving around and all.
我猜如果一動不動的話 肯定會好剃得多
- There's that. - Yeah.
- 確實是 - 耶
You know what I been thinking?
你知道我一直在想什麼嗎？
Well, they been telling us we need to buddy up
他們一直告訴我們要多交朋友
and I think we'd make pretty good buddies.
我想我們倆一定會成為好朋友
And how do you figure that?
你為什麼這麼想？
Well, you know, in that we have a lot in common.
你知道，我們有許多共同點
So, why do you cut dead people's hair, anyway?
為什麼你會給死人理發？
I'm studying to work in a funeral home.
我正在學習怎麼在殯儀館工作
You tell a lot of people that?
你跟很多人都這麼說的？
You actually chose the Marines because they got the best uniform?
你選擇海軍陸戰隊 只因為他們有最好的制服？
No sense being a hero if you don't look like one.
沒有英雄派頭的話 當了英雄也沒感覺
Jacks.
對J
Queens.
對Q
Shit.
他媽的
Do anything on that reservation but play cards, Chief?
酋長，你在保留區裡面除了玩牌 還幹過什麼？
All right, listen up, you sorry bunch of leathernecks!
好，都聽著 你們這幫可憐的陸戰隊員
We practice going over the side tomorrow
我們明天準備練習翻船舷
which means we ain't long for this piece of rock.
也就是說我們在這裡呆不久了
All right!
太棒了！
One more thing, any man who doesn't have his masturbation papers in order
還有件事，那些還沒有登記手淫用紙的
better get them signed by tomorrow night or he ain't going overseas.
最好在明晚前簽字 否則到海上可什麼都沒有
- I got mine already. - Oh, yeah. I'm square.
- 我已經有了 - 噢，好，那我就放心了
Wait. Why am I just hearing about this?
等一下，我怎麼頭一次聽說有這事？
That's horseshit, Franklin. I don't have to repeat everything twice for you.
別扯了，富蘭克林 我沒有義務把每件事都對你說兩遍
No, I didn't hear nothing about no masturbating papers.
沒人告訴我，會沒有手淫紙用
Heard they were running short.
聽說快發光了
You know, nobody tells me nothing. That's real nice, guys.
沒一個人告訴我 你們真太好了
All right, get your ass over to the officer in charge of records.
去找管登記的軍官去
Maybe he got some more left.
他可能還有一些
- Leave your smokes. I'll play for you. - Thanks, Mike.
- 把你的煙留下，我替你玩 - 謝謝，邁克
Listen, he calls you an idiot, you take it like a man, okay?
聽著，如果他管你叫白癡 你要像個爺們一樣頂住
Just do not leave without signing them.
不簽名就不要離開
- I appreciate it, Sergeant. - You got it.
- 十分感謝，中士 - 沒什麼
What the hell happened to your hair, Rene?
雷尼，你這個頭髮到底是怎麼回事？
Look like a goddamn corpse.
真他媽的像死人
Three points of contact on that rope at all times.
始終和繩子保持三個接觸點
Next four. Over the side.
後面四個，翻過去
Let's go. Keep moving.
別停下來
Just keep your eye on the guy below you.
看著腳下的人
That's all you gotta look at.
別的都不用管
Watch me, Doc, just watch me.
看我怎麼做，大夫，注意看
Keep three points of contact on the rope at all times.
始終和繩子保持三個接觸點
You see? No big thing.
看到了嗎？很簡單
Just one step at a time and keep your hands on the vertical rope.
一次下一步 手要一直抓住垂直的繩子
Remember, once you're in the boat move away from the rope.
記住，一旦下到船上，就離繩子遠點
Just make sure you keep three points of contact on the rope.
只要記住和繩子保持三個接觸點就行
I got him!
我去救他！
All right, get that man out of the water.
好，把那個人拉上來
Give me a hand.
幫我一下
Grab his pack.
抓住他的背包
Don't worry about him, Doc.
不用擔心他，大夫
All right, quit skylarking! Keep it moving!
都別笑了 繼續，別停下
He'll be fine.
他沒事的
Our target, Island X,
我們的目標：X島
is an ugly, smelly, dirty little scab of rock called lwo Jima.
那是一個醜陋、難聞、骯髒的 石頭小島，名叫Iwo Jima
It means "Sulfur Island," which accounts for the smell.
意思是「硫磺島」 因為島上都是硫磺味
Looks sort of like a burnt pork chop, you ask me.
如果你問我那是什麼味道 有點像燒焦了的排骨
After 20 straight days of bombing
在連續轟炸20天後
you won't find a blade of grass or a twig on it.
上面將會寸草不生 一根毛都找不到
It wasrt that pretty to start with.
不會是什麼漂亮的地方
Captain?
上尉？
Lwo's just five-and-a-half miles long, two-and-a-half wide.
硫磺島長5.5英里，寬2.5英里
There's a lump down at the bottom. That's Mount Suribachi.
底下有一塊高地，那是折缽山
On the maps in front of you the island is white.
在你們面前這張地圖上 這個島是白色的
Not much of it.
不是很白
The black dots represent known enemy emplacements.
黑點代表已知的敵人炮位
Coastal defense guns, dual-mount dual-purpose guns,
有岸防炮、雙聯裝高平兩用炮
covered artillery emplacements.
還有隱蔽的火炮掩體
Rifle pits, foxholes, antitank guns
戰壕、散兵坑、反坦克炮
machine guns, blockhouses, pillboxes, and earth-covered structures.
機槍、碉堡、地堡和地下工事
I don't see any barracks or any other structures.
我沒看見兵營和其他類型的建築
That's right.
確實如此
And we still don't know why.
原因我們還不清楚
Now, this isn't just any island to them.
這個島對他們來說非同尋常
This isn't Tarawa, Guam, Tinian, or Saipan.
這不是塔拉瓦島、關島、提尼安島 或者塞班島
This is Japanese soil, sacred ground.
這是日本的領土，他們神聖的土地
Twelve thousand Japanese defenders in eight square miles.
在這八平方英里的土地上 駐紮了一萬兩千名日本守軍
They will not leave politely, gentlemen.
他們可不會老老實實地離開，先生們
It's up to us to convince them.
所以要靠我們來「說服」他們
The 28th will land here at Green Beach.
28團準備在綠灘登陸
The 8th Ammo Company will land here to re-supply.
第八彈藥連在這裡登陸，提供補給
The Suribachi's guns are the biggest problem.
折缽山的火炮是最大的障礙
They can hit any point on the island.
它們能打到島上任何位置
We're sitting ducks until we take them out.
在搞定它們之前，我們都是靶子
That's our job.
這就是我們的任務
We cut across the island, right at the base, slit its throat, lop off its head.
我們就在底部把島切成兩段 割斷它的喉嚨，讓它腦袋搬家
And we take that mountain.
我們要奪下那座山
We take that mountain, we take their big guns.
我們奪下了那座山 就奪下了他們的大炮
We take their eyes.
而且挖掉了他們的眼睛
Okay, I'm heading in. Follow me.
我來領飛，跟著我
Let's put a good show on for the Marines.
我們給海軍陸戰隊亮一手
Close it up. Take it right down to the deck.
再靠近點，和甲板持平
Yeah, boys!
耶，小伙們！
Man overboard portside!
有人落水了！
See him?
看到他了嗎？
Throw me a line!
給我一根繩子！
He's right there.
他在那邊
- Where is he? - Watch out, watch out, watch out.
- 他在哪？ - 小心，小心
Hawaii's that way!
夏威夷在那邊！
Just keep paddling, Mac, we'll catch you on the way back!
繼續玩，馬克 我們回來的時候會接你的！
Hold on, they're gonna lower a raft!
堅持住，他們會放救生艇的！
They're not gonna stop.
他們不會停下來的
What?
什麼？
None of them are. They can't.
沒有一個會停下來的 他們不能
So much for "No man left behind."
這就是所謂的「不讓一個人掉隊」
- Sir. - Come on in.
- 長官 - 進來
Look, I've had to make a few other changes.
我不得不做一些其它改動
I'm promoting you to platoon sergeant.
我要提你當排副
- Thank you, sir. I appreciate it. - You bet.
- 謝謝，長官，我很感激 - 小意思
Trouble is, I already told my men I'd see them through this.
問題是，我已經告訴我的手下 我會和他們共患難
That your James Cagney impersonation?
你在模仿詹姆斯·卡格尼*？ （*美國電影演員 1942年學院獎最佳男演員）
'Cause I've heard better.
我見過演得比你好的
Well, I'll keep practicing, then.
這麼說我會繼續練習的
Look, this isn't your first time through this.
你也不是第一次參戰了
- You don't need to prove anything. - No, sir.
- 你不需要證明什麼 - 不需要，長官
You're not the best sergeant I've ever had,
你不是我見過的最好的中士
you're just the best one that's still walking.
你只是那些還能走路的人當中最好的
- Block's a good man. - Yes, sir, he is.
- 布洛克是個好戰士 - 是的，長官，他確實是
The men know him, he can step right in.
士兵們都熟悉他，他可以很快接替你
You know, I have actually thought this through.
你知道，我其實已經考慮過了
Platoon sergeant puts you further away from the bullets.
當了排副，你就能離子彈遠點
I already gave them my word, sir.
我已經答應過他們了，長官
I told them I'd bring them all home to their mothers
我說過要把他們全都活著帶回家見媽媽
which means I already lied to half of them. Can't lie to the rest.
現在我已經對一半人食言了 不能再騙另一半
- How are your men? - They'll do fine.
- 你的手下怎麼樣？ - 他們做得很好
Except maybe Gagnon.
大概只有蓋格南例外
Our own Tyrone Power?
我們自己的泰龍·鮑華*？ （*四十年代的好萊塢影星）
Yes, sir. He's a good man, just might be better use further back from the lines.
是的，長官，他是個好戰士 只不過在後方表現得更好
I'll use him as a runner.
我會讓他當傳令兵
All right. Thank you, sir.
好的，謝謝，長官
Now get out of here.
現在出去吧
Hear the good news, Doc? We're going in with the first waves.
聽到好消息了嗎，大夫？ 我們和第一波進攻的人一起去
Hey, you do that again I'll take your head off!
嘿，你再這麼幹的話 我會讓你腦袋搬家！
Fucking dominoes.
他媽的骨牌
Iggy, have you ever heard news you considered to be bad?
伊基，什麼消息對你來說才是壞消息？
The first ones off the ship, Doc.
第一批下船的人，大夫
Means we don't go over the side of the ship.
也就是說我們不用再翻船舷了
We hop on a tractor, they drive us right there.
我們搭乘拖船，他們帶我們過去
Oh, shit, that is good news.
噢，靠，這才是好消息
You see? What'd I tell you?
明白了吧？我告訴過你什麼來著？
What's going on?
發生什麼了？
Look at that.
快看
We're killing them!
我們正在屠宰他們！
We're killing them, Doc.
我們正在屠宰他們，大夫
I was promised 10 days of shelling.
說好了要炮轟十天
You're giving me three and saying that's the best you can do?
你現在說只能給我三天 還說你已經盡力了？
I don't give a shit! My men hit that beach with less than 10
我他媽的不管！ 如果十天不到就讓我的人搶灘
and I'll be taking them home to their mamas in buckets!
我只能帶著他們的骨灰 去見他們的媽媽了
Yeah, I know exactly why.
嗯，我知道是怎麼回事
Because every Navy man with a scrambled egg on his chest
因為每個胸前戴著金綬帶的海軍
wants to offload us here and sail to Japan
都想把我們扔在這裡，然後自己去日本
so they can be there for the big finish,
這樣他們就能在那邊見到大結局
tell their kids they captured the Emperor all by themselves.
然後告訴自己的孩子 他們親手抓住了天皇
Well, you aren't going to Japan unless we take this piece of shit island!
只要我們沒有拿下這個鳥島 你們就別想去日本！
These little pricks are dug in!
這些小鬼子都鑽在地底下呢！
Okay, appreciate that, Jim. Three days is a fucking beautiful thing.
好，吉姆，我很感激 三天真是太棒了
Sharpen your knife or bayonet?
需要磨匕首或刺刀嗎？
I'm okay.
我的不用
Jesus, lggy, just leave me alone, all right?
天，伊基 讓我一個人呆一會兒，行嗎？
How about you guys? Knife? Bayonet? Kick in the ass?
你們需要嗎？匕首？刺刀？ 還是給你們鼓鼓勁？
How about you, Doc? Sharpen your knife?
你呢，大夫？ 需要磨匕首嗎？
You sharpened it three times already.
已經被你磨過三次了
Well, then I better make sure I didn't nick it.
那我最好看一下有沒有缺口
Good man, Doc.
謝謝，大夫
- Hey, Doc. - Yeah.
- 嘿，大夫 - 在
When we land, try not to wave this kit around too much.
我們登陸後，別讓急救箱過於暴露
They got sharpshooters that are trained to look for them.
他們有狙擊手 對尋找這些目標做過訓練
And they know that if they take out a corpsman
他們知道如果放倒一個看護兵……
another dozen Marines will die unattended. All right?
就等於放倒幾十個臨死的陸戰隊員 知道嗎？
Okay, Mike.
明白，邁克
Yeah, right there.
耶，就聽這個
Close the damn door. For God's sake.
把他媽門關上，上帝
Yeah, like that's gonna help.
嗯，關上比較好
That your girlfriend, Chief?
酋長，女朋友的照片？
Bet she's a pretty damn good-looking squaw.
她肯定是個印第安美人
Bet you're missing her, and that little wigwam of yours.
他一定想她了，還有你們溫馨的小茅屋
Welcome, all Marines off lwo Jima.
歡迎所有準備前往硫磺島的陸戰隊員
We have a long-time wait...
我們等了很長時間……
It's what they do to prisoners,
他們就是這樣對待戰俘的
- at least the lucky ones. - Jesus.
- 至少這些還是幸運的 - 上帝
If I were you, cowpokes, I wouldn't think about waving a white bandanna.
牛仔們，如果我是你們的話 我肯定不會揮白手帕投降的
Poor Marines, so far from home for no good reason.
可憐的陸戰隊員們 莫名其妙地背井離鄉
Think of your girls back home, waiting for you.
想想你們的女友還在家裡等著你們
But a girl cannot stay home every night.
但是一個女人不可能每晚都守空房
So who do you think they're with tonight?
你認為她晚上會和誰為伴？
And will she let him kiss her? And will he comfort her at your funeral?
她會讓那個人吻她嗎？ 那個人會在你的葬禮上安慰她嗎？
This sweet music is to make you think of your girls back home
這首甜蜜的歌……
who are missing you.
會讓你們想起在家思念你們的女友
This is all for now. I'll see you tomorrow night.
今天就到這裡 明晚見
Gunners!
炮手！
Move, let's go! Let's go, get up on the berm!
快，別停下！ 快上防護堤！
Gunners!
炮手！
We're clear!
這邊安全！
Get up the berm!
上防護堤！
Baker Company, move out!
B連，繼續前進！
- Seen Second Platoon? - I don't see them.
- 看到二排的人了嗎？ - 沒看見
First Squad, move it out!
一班，繼續衝！
God, this place reeks.
上帝，這地方太臭了
- Go, go, go! - Move out!
- 沖，沖，衝！ - 快走！
Go, go, go, go! Go, go! Go! Go, go! Drop your packs! Go!
沖，沖，衝！沖，沖，衝！ 放下背包，快！
All clear!
齊了！
- Jesus, you needed some exercise? - He got lost.
- 天，你需要多鍛煉吧？ - 他走丟了
A hundred landing craft heading for one beach and this guy gets lost.
上百艘登陸艇都在一個海灘登陸 竟然還會走丟
Now I'm glad we did. Jesus, what a mess.
慶幸的是我們沒走失 天，亂作一團
Any theories why they ain't shooting?
他們一直沒開槍，你有什麼看法？
It's getting on my nerves.
這才讓我緊張
Maybe they're all dead.
他們可能死光了吧
What do you think, Doc? You think they're all dead?
你怎麼想，大夫？ 你認為他們都死了嗎？
Mike, take six men and bring that gun onto the beach.
邁克，帶六個人把那門炮抬到海灘上
Second Platoon, let's move out! Stay down. Come on.
二排，開始前進！ 快起來
Move! Move!
衝！衝！
- Get down! - Take cover!
- 趴下！ - 找掩體！
Move out!
衝！
Cover fire! Pour it on!
火力掩護！都給我開火！
Ray, shift your fire to the right, now!
雷，朝右邊射，快！
Corpsman!
看護兵！
I'm gonna sling your arm and then I'll give you a shot for the pain!
我會給你吊繃帶 然後再打止痛針
Move, move! Off the beach!
快，快！離開海灘！
Take cover!
找掩體！
You got a girl back home, Marine?
你家裡有女朋友嗎？
We're gonna make sure she sees you, all right?
我們保證她會再見到你的，好嗎？
I need pressure on this wound!
你幫他按住這個傷口！
Where's the fire coming from?
他們是從哪射擊的？
Where are they?
他們在哪？
Look for a flash, shoot at it!
找有火光的地方，向那裡射擊！
Let's go, let...
我們沖，我……
Twelve o'clock, take out the bunker!
十二點方向，拿下那個地堡！
You're over!
射高了！
Third Squad, forward! Move!
三班，前進！衝！
Where are they, sir?
他們在哪，長官？
We got ten o'clock! Ten o'clock, pillbox! Sergeant!
十點鐘方向 十點鐘方向有火力點！中士！
- Sergeant! I think I can clear that out. - What?
- 中士！我能搞定它 - 什麼？
All right, you go. Here.
好，你去，接著
Take these. Check your weapon.
拿著這些，檢查你的武器
Yeah? Go! Cover!
好了？衝！掩護！
Cover him!
掩護他！
Cover, cover!
掩護，掩護！
Son-of-a-bitch.
狗娘養的
Let's go! Go!
我們衝！衝！
Move it out!
快！
Go, go, go!
沖，沖，衝！
Down, down, down!
趴下，趴下，趴下！
It's clear.
搞定了
Good work.
幹得好
I thought you said it was clear!
你說你已經把它搞定了！
It was!
剛才是！
Shit, I guess they're not in there firing at us then.
媽的，我猜他們剛才沒在那裡射擊
Lindberg!
林德伯格！
Yeah!
在！
Light it up!
燒了它！
I'll cover you, Ice!
我來掩護你，冰人！
Don't cover shit! There's already enough people shooting!
別他媽再掩護了！ 開火的人已經夠多了！
One bullet and this thing goes up like a Roman candle!
一顆子彈，這東西就變煙花了！
Go! Shift fire!
衝！轉移火力！
Shift your fire!
轉移火力！
Go, go! Shift your fire!
沖，衝！轉移火力！
Go! Move it out!
衝！快！
Hit the deck! Stay down! Wait for support!
臥倒！別起來！等援兵！
Is this a bad battle or what?
這仗是不是搞砸了？
It's a fucking slaughter.
這他媽是屠殺
Christ Jesus!
上帝啊！
Get a machine gun team set up over here, now!
給我找個機槍組來 架在這裡，快！
Thank God! Tanks!
感謝上帝！坦克來了！
Runner! Get those tanks up here!
傳令兵！讓那些坦克到這邊來！
Oh, shit.
噢，天
Get down!
趴下！
Corporal, watch your left flank!
下士，小心你的左翼！
Let's go without them! Move out! Move out!
不用等它們了！ 沖，快衝！
Lggy, you gotta lift your side, he's gonna roll off.
伊基，你那邊抬高點 不然他會掉下來的
Got it, Doc!
知道了，大夫！
Incoming!
炮彈來了！
Move, move, move, move!
快，快，快！
Keep moving!
別停下！
Get that LVT up on the beach!
讓那輛登陸車上岸來！
You're next, pal, we're getting you out of here.
兄弟，下一個就是你 我們會帶你離開這裡
Move it!
快抬！
Great news.
好消息
Maybe if you live up on Camp Tarawa, 'cause that's where we're headed.
是不是要在塔拉瓦營地享福了 我們正要去那兒
Not you and me.
你和我可不會去
Captain Severance asked me who else was in that picture,
塞沃倫斯上尉問我那張照片裡還有誰？
and Christ if I could remember,
我怎麼可能記得
but it was Mike and Doc and Franklin and me and Hank Hansen
但我知道肯定有邁克、大夫 富蘭克林、漢克·漢森和我
but I just remembered, you were there, too.
我剛剛想起來了，你當時也在
I wasrt there.
我不在
'Course you were.
你當然在
Neither was Hank. He raised the first flag.
漢克也不在 他插的是第一面旗
It was Harlon Block that raised that one.
照片上那面是哈龍·布洛克插的
Shit. I told them it was Hank.
媽的，我告訴他們是漢克
You werert there, Mr. Smart Ass, how'd you know it was Harlon?
聰明先生，如果當時你不在的話 你怎麼會知道是哈龍插的那面？
- You tell them it was me? - No. Like I said, I just remembered.
- 你跟他們說是我幹的？ - 沒有，我說了，只是剛想起來
Good, keep your mouth shut.
好，那就把嘴巴管緊了
They know there was somebody else, you can see it in the picture.
他們知道當時肯定有其他人 你從照片上也能看出來
Then pick someone dead.
那就找個死人
They don't want somebody dead, you dumb redskin,
他們不想要死人 你這個印第安傻佬
they want to ship us back to the States.
他們想要把我們送回國內去
What did I tell you?
我告訴過你什麼來著？
I wasrt there.
當時我不在
- You hear? - All right.
- 聽明白了嗎？ - 好吧
Just settle down.
冷靜一下
- I'm not going anywhere. - You're not going anywhere.
- 我哪也不去 - 你哪也不去
Who the hell says?
誰說的？
This is horseshit.
靠
You wounded, son?
你受傷了？
No, sir.
沒有，長官
Well, did you take out a nest of Japs butt-naked with your bare hands?
你空手幹掉了一幫光屁股的日本鬼子？
'Cause if I'm gonna give up my seat to a hero
因為如果要我把座位讓給英雄
he better have a good goddamn story to tell.
他最好有個動聽的故事
No, sir.
沒有，長官
Then enjoy it, 'cause they'll forget you before Christmas.
那就去享樂吧 因為他們在聖誕節前就把你遺忘了
The sixth man, you got a name?
第六個人，你知道名字了？
Sorry, still don't remember.
對不起，還是沒有想起來
It's a damn shame, 'cause I promised the Major you'd know who it was.
這太丟人了 因為我向少校保證你知道那個人
Fact, you not knowing throws a doubt on you
事實上，如果你真不知道……
being one of the flag-raisers yourself.
難免讓人懷疑你有沒有參與插旗
Since no one wants to be embarrassed, the moment you land
既然沒人想要尷尬的場面 那麼一旦飛機著陸……
they'll turn you around, ship you off to Okinawa
他們就會掉頭，把你送回衝繩
in time to meet your buddies on the beach.
你還來得及在海灘上見到戰友
So, why don't you stop screwing with me? Give me a damn name.
所以你為什麼就不能誠實點呢？ 我就需要他媽的一個名字而已
Gangway! Gangway! Let's go, let's go! Gangway!
閃開！閃開！ 快點，快！閃開！
Where the hell is that son-of-a-bitch? Hayes! Hayes?
那個狗娘養的到底在哪？ 海耶斯！海耶斯？
Hayes, get your red ass over here!
海耶斯，快他媽給我過來！
Make me look like I don't know what my own men are doing
手下插了一面跟我媽房子那麼大的旗子
with a flag the size of my mother's house?
我這個當上司的竟然不知道？ 這讓我很難堪，知道嗎？
God damn it, Ira, you shouldn't have lied to me.
他媽的，艾拉 你不該對我撒謊的
You made me look like a complete asshole.
你讓我看起來像個徹底的白癡
We're gonna miss you around here. Good luck.
我們會想念你的 祝你好運
Now your name's in the paper, too.
現在你的名字也上報紙了
Just heard your doctor say we're postponing your operation.
剛剛聽大夫說 我們要推遲你的手術
You're being shipped back to the mainland.
你將會被送回本土
Everybody who saw that picture thought planting the flag meant victory.
每個見過那張照片的人 都會認為插上那面旗子就意味著勝利
That's all they wanted to know. Victory.
勝利，他們想知道的無非就是這個
Within a few weeks of that picture being taken, half the men in it were dead.
那張照片照了沒多久 上面的人就死了一半
Mrs. Hansen! Mrs. Hansen! Did you know Hank was a hero?
漢森夫人！漢森夫人！ 你知道漢克成了英雄嗎？
- Are you proud of him, Mrs. Hansen? - What was he like as a boy?
- 你為他感到驕傲嗎，漢森夫人？ - 他在童年時怎麼樣？
Look this way, please, ma'am.
請看這邊，夫人
What do you have to say about your son?
關於你的兒子，你想說些什麼？
But somehow being a part of it meant something.
但是不管怎麼樣 你身在其中總是有意義的
Looking at it, you could believe their sacrifice was not a waste.
看看這個 你會相信他們不是白白犧牲的
Yeah, I might have thought that was Harlon, too.
嗯，我可能也會認為那是哈龍
It is.
就是他
Belle, their names are right here. It's not him.
蓓爾，他們的名字都列出來了 裡面沒有他
And he would be alive and sitting right here if it wasrt for you.
要不是因為你 他應該還活著，和我們一起坐在這裡
You think about that when you look at his picture, Ed.
你看他照片的時候 好好想想吧，艾德
And I need to rush home and change
我需要馬上回家換身衣服
because there's the Governor's banquet and then there's the parade.
因為馬上有個州長的宴會 然後還有遊行
Imagine, the Governor is coming here to meet us.
想像一下，州長會來見我們
Now, I'm wearing blue so, if...
我打算穿藍色的，如果……
- Are you going to change? - We interrupt this program to bring you
- 你準備換衣服嗎？ - 很抱歉，我們要中斷這個節目……
a special news bulletin from CBS World News.
插播一則最新的CBS世界新聞特別報道
A press association has just announced that President Roosevelt is dead.
一個記者招待會剛剛宣佈 羅斯福總統去世的消息
The President died of a cerebral hemorrhage.
總統死於腦溢血
All we know so far is that the President died at Warm Springs in Georgia.
到目前為止，據我們得到的信息 總統是在佐治亞州的溫泉市去世的
Further updates every hour.
我們將每小時報道一次最新消息
Temperatures will remain the same today,
今天氣溫沒有明顯變化
in the mid-30s to low 40s with clear skies.
天氣晴朗，氣溫在35度到40度左右
Hello?
喂？
Yes. Of course.
是的，當然
No, we understand. It wouldn't be right.
不，我們明白 確實不適宜
Thank you.
謝謝
Here he is, gentlemen. Senator Boyd, Senator Robson.
他來了，先生們 這是參議員博伊德和羅伯遜
Senator Haddigan. I'd like you to meet Private First Class Ira Hayes.
還有參議員哈迪根 這就是一等兵艾拉·海耶斯
Damn good to meet you.
真高興見到你
Proud to make your acquaintance, son.
很榮幸認識你
Sorry?
對不起？
That's Pima Indian talk, boy, don't you know your own language?
這是皮瑪印第安話 你聽不懂家鄉話？
Took forever to memorize the damn gibberish.
我可花了好長時間才記住這些土話
Sorry, I've been away from the reservation too long, Senator.
對不起，參議員 我離開印第安保留區太久了
- Doc. - Ira.
- 大夫 - 艾拉
And now, the heroes of lwo Jima!
接下來是硫磺島的英雄們出場了！
- That's you. - Go, go, go, go. Go.
- 輪到你們出場了 - 快去，快去
Please welcome
讓我們熱烈歡迎……
Navy Corpsman John "Doc" Bradley,
海軍看護兵，綽號「大夫」的 約翰·布萊德利
Private First Class Ira Hayes,
一等兵艾拉·海耶斯
Private First Class Rene Gagnon!
一等兵雷尼·蓋格南！
Holy shit.
我的媽呀
Come in, come in, come in. Bud Gurber, Treasury Department.
請進，請進 我是財政部的巴德·戈伯
- Rene Gagnon. - Bud Gurber.
- 雷尼·蓋格南 - 巴德·戈伯
- You showing the boys the sights? - We saw a hell of a ball game.
- 帶他們到周圍參觀了嗎？ - 我們看了一場精彩的球賽
That's great. The bar's there, help yourself.
不錯 酒吧在那邊，請自己倒
I got some briefing sheets for you here,
我這裡有些演說提綱
just some simple things we want you to say.
僅僅是一些我們想要你們說的話
Mostly, "Buy bonds," can't say that too often.
最多的就是「買債券」 但也不能說得太頻繁
Itineraries, those are changing every couple minutes.
這是行程安排 但可能過一陣就變一次
Everybody wants to meet you guys.
大家都想親眼看看你們這些英雄
I got women sending up envelopes with stockings in them,
女人們甚至把長筒襪 塞在信封裡寄給你們
notes written in lipstick. We won't mention that to the press, am I right?
還有用口紅寫的便條，當然我們不會 對媒體提這些的，我說得對吧？
Have a drink, for Christ's sake.
暢飲吧，看在上帝份上
My God, what you boys must have seen over there.
我的天，你們在那邊看到的東西
I've been watching the newsreels.
我在新聞短片裡也都看到了
Jesus Christ, that was a fight and a half.
上帝啊，除了打仗還是打仗
So, we got a hell of a lot of money to raise, not a lot of time.
所以我們要籌很多錢 但是時間卻不多
White House tomorrow, then we trot you over
明天先去白宮，然後就要四處轉
to shake hands with a couple of hundred Congressmen
跟幾百位國會議員握手
who won't pull a penny out of their pockets.
他們不會從自己的錢包裡掏一分錢
Politicians and actors.
這些政治家演戲的本領強得很……
You put them in a restaurant together,
如果你把他們聚到一家餐廳裡
they'd die of old age before picking up the check.
他們等到老死都不會付賬
Then New York City, Times Square,
……然後是紐約的時代廣場
dinners with various hoi polloi, then Chicago...
和各色各樣的老百姓聚餐 接著是芝加哥……
Who are these "Gold Star Mothers"?
這些「金星媽媽」是誰？
That's what we're calling the mothers of the dead flag-raisers.
是那些犧牲的旗手們的母親
You present each mother with a flag,
你們給每位母親一面旗幟
they say a few words, people will shit money.
再讓她們說點話 然後人們就能擠出錢來
It'll be so moving.
那將是非常令人感動的
But this says Hank Hansers mom.
但是這上面寫的是漢克·漢森的母親
Lovely woman. She knows how close you and her son were.
好女人，她知道你和她兒子有多親近
He wrote home about you.
他在家信裡提到過你
She is very, very much looking forward to meeting you.
她非常非常地盼望見到你
Hank wasrt in the picture.
照片上沒有漢克
Sorry?
你說什麼？
Hank didn't raise that flag.
漢克沒有去插那面旗
He raised the other one, the real flag.
他插的是另一面，真的旗子
The what? The real... The real flag? There's a real flag?
什麼？真的…… 真的旗子？還有一面真的旗子？
Yeah, ours was the replacement flag.
是的，我們插的是替代品
We put it up when they took the other one down.
他們把另一面拿下來時 我們就把它插上去了
Am I the only one getting a headache here? You know about this?
這裡我是不是唯一感到頭痛的？ 你知道這件事嗎？
It was after it was already in the papers.
刊登在報紙上之後才知道的
The mothers had already been told, but...
那些母親們已經被告知了，但是……
That's it, that's beautiful. Yeah, that's beautiful.
夠了 做得好，做得真好
Yeah, why tell me?
為什麼告訴我？
I'm only the guy that has to explain it to 150 million Americans.
只有我能向1.5億美國同胞解釋真相？
Who is in the goddamn picture?
到底誰在那張該死的照片上？
Are any of you guys in the goddamn picture?
你們都在那張該死的照片上？
Yeah, we're in the goddamn picture.
對，我們都在那張該死的照片上
Six guys raising a flag over lwo Jima. Victory is ours.
六個人在硫磺島插了一面旗 勝利是屬於我們的
You're three of them, right?
你們是其中的三個，對吧？
This was the fifth day, sir. The battle went on for 35 more.
這只是第5天發生的事，先生 戰鬥持續了35天以上
Well, what'd you do, raise a goddamn flag every time you stopped for lunch?
你們是幹什麼的？ 每次停下來吃飯時，升一面該死的旗？
Can I hit this guy?
我能教訓一下這個傢伙嗎？
You know what, I don't give a shit, you're in the picture,
你們知道嗎？我根本不在乎 你們在照片上，你們升了那面旗子……
you raised the flag, that's the story we're selling, boys.
這就是我們要講給所有人聽的故事 明白嗎？
Are you deaf? Hank isn't in the picture. Harlon is in the picture.
你聾了嗎？ 照片上的不是漢克，是哈龍
Well, who the fuck is Harlon?
好吧，那他媽到底誰是哈龍？
Harlon Block. That's whose mother should be here if anyone's should be.
哈龍·布洛克 如果我們能來這裡，他母親也應該來
You know, I think this whole damn thing is a farce, you ask me.
知道嗎，如果你讓我說的話 整件事就是一場該死的滑稽戲
You know what they're calling this bond drive? The Mighty Seventh.
你們知道他們管這次籌款活動 叫什麼嗎？叫「偉大的第七次」
They might've called it the
他們或許應該稱它為……
"We're Flat Fucking Broke And Can't Even Afford Bullets
「我們他媽的一窮二白了 甚至連子彈都買不起……」
"So We're Begging For Your Pennies" bond drive,
「所以我們需要你們的施捨」
but it didn't have quite the ring. They could've called it that, though,
但是它沒那麼響亮…… 雖然他們可以這麼叫
because the last four bond drives came up so short
因為前四次的籌款成績太差了
we just printed money instead.
我們只好加印鈔票來應付
Ask any smart boy on Wall Street, he'll tell you
但你在華爾街隨便問個聰明的傢伙 他都會告訴你……
our dollar is next to won'thless, we borrowed so much.
我們的美元快成白紙了 我們已經借了太多錢
And nobody is lending any more. Ships aren't being built.
沒有人再會借給我們 軍艦造不了，坦克造不了
Tanks aren't being built. Machine guns, bazookas, hand grenades, zip.
機關鎗、火箭炮、手榴彈也是 甚至連拉鏈也不例外
You think this is a farce? You want to go back to your buddies?
現在你還認為這是一個滑稽戲？ 你想回去和你的戰友並肩作戰？
Well, stuff some rocks in your pockets before you get on the plane
好，不過在上飛機前 要往口袋裡面塞一些石頭
because that's all we got left to throw at the Japanese.
因為我們只能指望著 用這些扔日本鬼子了
And don't be surprised if your plane doesn't make it off the runway
而且如果你們的飛機飛不出跑道 也不要大驚小怪
because the fuel dumps are empty.
因為油箱是空的
And our good friends, the Arabs, are only taking bullion.
我們的好朋友，阿拉伯人，只收金條
If we don't raise $14 billion,
如果我們籌不到140億美元的話
and that's million with a "B," this war is over by the end of the month.
注意是140億不是140萬 那麼這場戰爭就會在月底結束
We make a deal with the Japanese, we give whatever they want
到時候我們會和日本人達成協議 他們想要什麼，我們都會給
and we come home, because you've seen them fight,
我們回家 因為你們會看到他們還在奮鬥
and they sure as shit ain't giving up.
他們拚死抵抗到最後
$14 billion.
140億
The last three drives didn't make that much all together.
前三次加起來也沒有籌到這麼多
People on the street corners,
街上的行人們……
they looked at this picture and they took hope.
當他們看到了這張照片 他們就看到了希望
Don't ask me why, I think it's a crappy picture myself.
別問我為什麼 我個人覺得那只是一張蹩腳照片
You can't even see your faces.
在照片上甚至連你們的臉都看不清
But it said we can win this war, are winning this war,
但是它告訴我們，這場戰爭能贏 或者說我們正在贏
we just need you to dig a little deeper.
只需要你們再出一點力
They want to give us that money.
他們就會給我們錢
No, they want to give it to you.
不，他們想給的是你們
But you, you don't want to ask for it. You don't want to give them hope.
但是你們，你們不想接受它 你們不想給他們帶來希望
You want to explain about this person and that flag.
你們只想解釋照片上的人和那面旗子
Well, that's your choice.
好吧，這是你們的選擇
Because if we admit we made a mistake, that's all anybody'll talk about
因為如果你們承認我們犯了一個錯誤 那所有的人都會談論這個……
and that will be that.
到時肯定是另一番局面……
Gentlemen.
先生們
Mr. President, here they are.
總統先生，他們來了
- Well, hello. Good to see you. - Mr. President.
- 你們好，很高興見到你們 - 總統先生
Darn good to see you, boys.
非常高興見到你們
Heard you had a hell of a fight on your hands out there, hell of a fight.
聽說你們在那邊的仗打得很艱苦 非常激烈
Yes, sir.
是的，先生
Ira, you're off the Gila River Reservation in Arizona, am I right?
艾拉，你是來自亞利桑那州的 吉拉河保留區，我說得對吧？
Yes, Mr. President.
是的，總統先生
Being an Indian, you are a truer American than any of us.
作為一個印第安人 你是比我們更地道的美國人
Bet your people are proud to see you wear that uniform.
你家鄉的人們看到你穿這身軍裝 肯定以你為榮
Very proud, sir.
他們十分引以為豪，先生
They should be.
他們肯定會
Well, I want to thank you for coming all this way to Washington to help us out.
謝謝你們能來華盛頓幫助我們解困
You fought for a mountain in the Pacific
你們已經為了太平洋的一座小山奮鬥過
now we need you to fight for a mountain of cash.
現在我們需要你們 為了「金山」再奮鬥一次
- And I don't expect you'll let us down. - No, sir.
- 希望不會讓我們失望 - 不會的，先生
Good. Go get it.
好，奪下它
That's the end of this ceremony.
歡迎儀式就先到這裡
Let's take a look at this famous photo over here, see if I can pick you out.
現在讓我們再來看看這張著名的照片 看看是否我能把你們都認出來
My gosh. There you are.
天，這個是你
Boys. Boys, this one's on me. To those who can't be with us.
夥計們，這杯我請客 敬那些不能和我們一起來的兄弟
Yes, sir.
是，長官
Excuse me, Mr. Gagnon. May we have your autograph?
勞駕，蓋格南先生 能給我簽個名嗎？
I suppose.
我想沒問題
And your name is?
你叫什麼名字？
I don't know about you, but I get the impression
我不知道你們怎麼想 但我突然發現……
I'm drinking with the wrong heroes.
我找錯英雄喝酒了
You're such a hero. I feel honored to be in your presence.
你真是一個英雄 能見到你真的很榮幸
That's just not true.
別這麼想
That's professional work. Here, to professionals.
那確實需要專業技能 來，敬專業人才
Here they are. You're the guys in the photograph, right?
他們在這裡 你們就是照片上的人，對吧？
I heard you were on the train.
我聽說你們也在這列車上
Let me shake your hands, John Tennack.
來握個手，我叫約翰·田納克
John Bradley.
約翰·布萊德利
These boys are with me, Harvard and Yale types, didn't fight a lick.
這些都是我的同伴，哈佛、耶魯 的讀書人，甚至連架都沒打過
Pappies all rich sons-of-bitches.
父親都是狗娘養的有錢人
Boys, shake hands with some real war heroes.
快跟這些真正的戰鬥英雄握下手
Excuse me for one moment.
失陪一下
You can buy them a drink while you're at it.
你既然來了，就該給他們買酒
That's right. Drinks for these men all the way around.
沒問題，一路上都要為這些英雄乾杯
And you're the other one, aren't you? John Tennack, Tennack Homes.
你是另外的一位，不是嗎？ 約翰·田納克，田納克房地產公司
- Rene Gagnon. - Pleased to meet you.
- 雷尼·蓋格南 - 很高興見到你
Have a drink, come on. And here's my card.
來，喝一杯 這是我的名片
Listen to me, Rene,
聽我說，雷尼
when you get finished being famous you come see me
等你出完名後，要記得來找我
because if you can sell bonds, you can sell homes.
因為如果你能賣債券的話 你就肯定能賣房子
Now, they're not gonna build homes anymore, they're gonna deliver them.
現在，他們不準備再建房子了 而是運房子
- You heard of prefab homes? - No, sir.
- 你聽說過活動房屋沒有？ - 沒有，先生
Well, you will. And you hang on to that card and you come see me, you hear?
你會知道的，不要把名片弄丟了 記得來找我，聽明白了嗎？
- All right? - Certainly will.
- 好嗎？ - 一定會的
All right.
沒事了
This sure takes it, huh, Doc?
你確定應該這樣下去，大夫？
If Mike and the guys could see us.
如果邁克和其他人看到我們這樣
Yeah, they'd hardly believe it, would they?
嗯，他們很難相信，不是嗎？
Harlon!
哈龍！
Franklin!
富蘭克林！
Can you imagine Franklin
你能想像……
on this train
富蘭克林在這餐車裡……
eating at the dining car with all the silver?
用銀餐具享用晚餐？
We shouldn't be here, Doc.
我們不應該在這裡的，大夫
There's gonna be a Hallelujah Day
哈利路亞的好日子就要來臨
When the boys have all come home to stay
當所有戰士都能回到溫暖的家
And a million bands begin to play
百萬個樂隊一起歌唱
We'll be dancing the Victory Polka
我們會跳勝利的波爾卡舞
And when we've lit the torch of liberty
當我們點亮自由的火炬
In each blacked-out land across the sea
穿越海洋照亮每處黑色的土地
Ira! Hey, Ira! We heard the picture was posed!
艾拉！嘿，艾拉！ 我聽說照片是擺拍的！
What?
什麼？
We heard you posed the picture!
我聽說你們是擺拍的！
Hey, Doc!
嘿，大夫！
We're bigger than life, Doc!
比我們真人還大，大夫！
And we'll heave a mighty sigh
我們會吐出一個有力的歎息
When each gal can kiss the boy she kissed goodbye
當每個女孩都能再吻一次她吻別的男孩
And they'll come marching down Fifth Avenue
他們會手牽手穿過第五大街
The United Nations in review
迎來舉國歡慶的場面
When this lovely dream has all come true
當這個美麗的夢想變為了現實
We'll be dancing the Victory Polka
我們會跳勝利的波爾卡舞
Good job.
幹得好
Thank you.
謝謝
Thank you, girls!
謝謝你們，姑娘們！
And now,
現在……
here are the men you've been waiting to meet,
你們一直想見的人已經來到了這裡
the men in white.
白色雕像的上的人
Right behind me here, the heroes of lwo Jima,
現在就站在我後面 他們是硫磺島的英雄們：
Private First Class Rene Gagnon,
一等兵雷尼·蓋格南！
Private First Class Ira Hayes,
一等兵艾拉·海耶斯！
and Navy Corpsman John "Doc" Bradley!
和海軍看護兵，綽號「大夫」 的約翰·布萊德利！
Thank you.
謝謝大家
It's good of you people to come out tonight in support of the war effort.
感謝大家今晚前來為戰爭的勝利 出一分力
We really need you to buy bonds, that's for sure.
可以肯定的是 我們真的需要你們購買債券
'Cause we can't win the war without your help.
因為沒有你們的幫助 我們不可能打贏這場戰爭
As far as us being the heroes of lwo Jima,
雖然到目前為止 我們一直被當作硫磺島的英雄看待
that's just not the case.
但實際上不是那麼回事
We really didn't do much at all.
我們真的沒有做出什麼貢獻
Especially him.
特別是他
Especially me.
特別是我
I was just a runner. That's it.
我只是個傳令兵，僅此而已
We put up a flag.
我們樹了一面旗子
The pole we attached it to was heavy, so it took a number of us.
由於旗桿很重 所以需要我們幾個人一起努力
We had our picture taken doing it.
這個鏡頭恰好被拍了下來
The real heroes are dead on that island.
但真正的英雄是 那些在島上犧牲的戰士們
And we'd appreciate it if you bought bonds in honor of them. Thank you.
如果你們能買債券來慰藉英靈 我們會很感激，謝謝
Jump on any grenades, Ira?
艾拉，你用身體撲過手榴彈嗎？
Take out any machine gun nests I missed?
摧毀過我錯過的機槍掩體嗎？
At least I fired my weapon.
至少我開過槍
All right, knock it off.
行了，別吵了
You hit anything or were you too drunk then, too?
你打中過任何東西嗎？ 還是因為你喝得太多了？
What?
你說什麼？
Guys! Come on!
大家，別這樣！
Stop it. Knock it off.
停下，別吵了
The tall man with the high hat will be coming down your way
戴著高帽子的巨人會來到你們身邊
Get your savings out when you hear him shout
當你聽到他的呼喊後 你要把自己的積蓄拿出來
"Any bonds today?"
今天還有沒有債券？
Bonds of freedom that's what I'm selling
我正在賣的就是象徵自由的債券
Rene, right here. Sit between these two boys.
雷尼，坐這裡 你坐中間
Here comes the freedom man
自由的人們已經來到
Asking you to buy a share of freedom today
今天讓你們也來購買自由
...for us and they need our help.
……為了我們，他們需要我們的幫助
And, if you think about it, I think you'll realize
如果你認真想過的話 我認為你會意識到……
that buying more bonds is not just the right thing to do
買更多的債券不僅僅是正確的行為
but the only thing to do.
而且是我們唯一能作的貢獻
Yes, this war has gone on too long.
沒錯，這場戰爭持續了太長時間
We have given too many lives. And its cost...
太多的人為此犧牲了 這個代價……
- Chocolate or strawberry, sir? - Strawberry.
- 巧克力醬還是草莓醬，先生？ - 草莓醬
...has been far too high.
……對我們來說太高了
But if we waver now,
但是如果我們現在動搖的話
if we don't dig deep and give more than we think we can
如果我們不能堅持下去 不能作出更多貢獻的話
then those sacrifices would be wasted...
那麼那些戰士們就白白犧牲了
Chocolate or strawberry, sir?
巧克力醬還是草莓醬，先生？
...and those lives lost in vain.
……那些生命就沒有意義了
Let's move! Go, go!
衝！快！快！
Easy Six, this is Easy Two, over. Where the hell are our tanks?
E6，這是E2，完畢 我們的坦克到底在哪？
Stuck in the sand. Captain says you're to go without them.
陷進沙裡了 上尉說你們要自己沖了
Christ.
上帝
That's real good work you're doing there, Rene.
你這差事真不賴，雷尼
All right, prepare to move out. Pass the word.
好，準備衝出去 傳達命令
Second Platoon! Move! Move! Move!
二排！衝！衝！衝！
All right, Second Platoon, on your feet! Let's move out!
二排，注意！ 我們衝出去！
Jackass.
蠢蛋
Go, go! Move, move, move!
快，快！沖，沖，衝！
Corpsman!
看護兵！
Second Platoon, move out!
二排，衝出去！
Doc!
大夫！
Doc, get out of there!
大夫，離開那邊！
Corpsman!
看護兵！
Doc!
大夫！
Doc, get the hell out of there!
大夫，快離開那邊！
May I have your attention, please.
請注意
Train number 48 with service from New York City, Boston,
48次列車從紐約發車，途經波士頓
Rochester, New York,
紐約州的羅切斯特市……
Toledo, Ohio, and South Bend, Indiana is now arriving on Track 7.
俄亥俄州的托萊多和印第安那州的南 本德，現在在7號站台進站
Train number 48 now arriving on Track number 7.
48次列車在7號站台進站
Okay, let's go. Let's go.
好了，我們走，我們走
- Come on, boys. - Let's go.
- 快點 - 我們走
- Watch your step, ma'am. - Thank you very much.
- 小心腳下 - 非常感謝
Ladies and gentlemen, may I present the heroes of lwo Jima.
女士們，先生們 請讓我介紹硫磺島的英雄們
Navy Corpsman John "Doc" Bradley.
海軍看護兵，綽號「大夫」 的約翰·布萊德利！
Private First Class Ira Hayes.
一等兵艾拉·海耶斯
And Private First Class Rene Gagnon.
和一等兵雷尼·蓋格南
Rene! That's my boyfriend!
雷尼！那是我男朋友！
Who the hell is that?
那人是誰？
I don't know.
不知道
- Rene, is that your girl? - Hey, what do they call you?
- 雷尼，那是你的妞？ - 嘿，你叫什麼？
How about a photo? Hey, look at that!
來照張相怎樣？嘿，瞧啊！
What's your name, doll? What's your name?
美女，你叫什麼名字？ 你叫什麼
Hey, she's a beauty.
她真是個美人
Let's go find a saloon.
咱們去找間酒吧
Smile, boys. Give them their money's won'th.
笑一個，小伙子們 讓他們知道自己的錢沒白花
Hey, Doc, how's the tour going for you?
「大夫」，你覺得 這次巡迴演講怎麼樣？
Thank you.
謝謝
Where exactly are you staying?
你住哪兒？
- I'm not sure yet. - Just forget about that.
- 我還沒決定 - 那就別操心了
Senator, I'd like you to meet Corpsman John Bradley.
參議員，我介紹你認識 看護兵約翰·布萊德利
- Doc, right? - Yes, sir. Nice to meet you, Senator.
- 「大夫」，對吧？ - 是的，很高興認識你，參議員
Good to meet you, young man.
很高興認識你，年輕人
Now, we appreciate everything you've done and everything you're doing.
對你們做過的和正在做的一切 我們感激不盡
- Thank you, sir. - Quite all right.
- 謝謝，先生 - 不客氣
This is Captain White.
這是懷特上校
- Colonel Johns. - We're proud of you, Corpsman.
- 約翰斯上校 - 我們為你驕傲，看護兵
And then Colonel McCourtney.
還有麥考特尼上校
- Major General Green. - Nice to meet you.
- 格林少將 - 認識你很高興
Senator, this is Private First Class Ira Hayes.
參議員，這是一等兵艾拉·海耶斯
Of course!
是他沒錯！
Now I hear you used a tomahawk on those Japs. Is that true, Chief?
我聽說你用印第安戰斧砍那些日本鬼子 這是真的嗎，「酋長」？
No, sir.
不是，先生
Well, tell them you did, makes a better story, huh?
哦，那就跟他們說是真的 把故事講得更好聽點，怎樣？
- Attaboy. - This is Captain Green.
- 好小伙子 - 這是格林上校
John?
約翰？
Madeline Evelley. I recognize you from all the photographs. I'm Hank's mom.
我是瑪德琳·伊芙利，我看過照片 所以能認出你，我是漢克的媽媽
It's so nice to meet you, ma'am. Hank was always talking about you.
見到你真是太好了，夫人 漢克經常談起你
This is PFC Rene Gagnon.
這是一等兵雷尼·蓋格南
Pleasure to meet you, son. Thanks for everything.
幸會幸會，感謝你做的一切
- My pleasure. - Not at all.
- 不用謝 - 別客氣
Ira, I'd like you to meet Mrs. Strank, Mike's mom.
艾拉，我讓你見見斯特蘭克太太 她是邁克的媽媽
It's all right.
好了，好了
When I got the telegram, I...
接到電報的時候，我……
I don't know what I'm trying to say here.
我不知道該說什麼好
Knowing he was with you that day and seeing him in that photograph,
當我聽說那天他和你在一起 又在那張照片上看到了他
I don't know why it makes me feel better, but it does.
我就感覺好受點了 不知為什麼，可我真的好受點了
- It's so silly, isn't it? - No, it's not.
- 這很傻，對吧？ - 不，不傻
How are you, son? Thank you very much.
你好嗎，小伙子？ 非常感謝
We're the largest furniture wholesaler in Illinois.
我們是伊利諾伊州最大的傢俱批發商
Thank you. Excuse me.
謝謝，失陪了
- I'll make sure he calls. - Well, thank you. Thank you.
- 我會讓他打電話來的 - 哦，謝謝，謝謝你
Are you Rene?
你是雷尼？
Yes, ma'am.
是的，太太
I'm Franklirs mother.
我是富蘭克林的媽媽
It's an honor to meet you, ma'am.
認識你是我的榮幸，太太
I'm Pauline, Rene's girlfriend.
我是波琳，雷尼的女朋友
Would you mind?
你不介意吧？
Paper said that's Hank,
報紙上說那就是漢克
and I honestly can't tell.
可是說實話，我認不出來
It's horrible of a mother not to know her own son, isn't it?
當媽的認不出自己兒子可真糟糕 你說是吧？
But that's him, isn't it?
可是那就是他，對嗎？
Well, to be honest, ma'am, it happened so quick,
唔，說實話，事情發生得太快了
and with everything that was going on
當時情況又很亂
it's kind of hard to remember who was where.
要記住哪些人在場有點難
But...
不過……
Yeah, I think... I think that's where he was.
沒錯，我想…… 我想他當時就在那個位置
That's Hank.
那就是漢克
Thank you.
謝謝
Excuse me.
失陪了
I'm so sorry for your loss.
對您的損失我很難過
Take him outside.
帶他出去
I'm Pauline.
我是波琳
- Very nice to meet you. - Hi, nice to meet you.
- 很高興認識你 - 嗨，很高興認識你
He was the best Marine I ever knew.
在我認識的陸戰隊員裡，他是最好的
Thank you.
謝謝
- You okay, Chief? - Oh, Christ!
- 你沒事吧，酋長？ - 哦，天哪！
I'm okay.
我沒事
Yeah, you look it. You're gonna screw this up, aren't you?
對，我看你也沒事 你是打算把這事攪黃，對吧？
You're gonna screw it up for all of us.
你打算為我們大家把這事攪黃
I've got him.
我扶他走
Get some sleep, Ira.
去睡會兒吧，艾拉
- Mike? - Yeah?
- 邁克？ - 嗯？
- You see this? - What?
- 你看見了嗎？ - 什麼？
- Mike! - Oh, shit, go!
- 邁克！ - 我操，衝啊！
He's killing me!
他殺了我了！
Hey, Doc, you think they got them all?
大夫，你看他們 是不是把鬼子都幹掉了？
What?
什麼？
Well, they're not shooting at us. Maybe we killed them all.
現在沒人朝我們開火 說不定我們已經把他們殺光了
Or they ran off in the night or something.
或者是他們趁晚上溜走了
Or they're waiting for us to start climbing.
也可能是在等我們往山上爬
Third Platoon! Grab your gear, we're going up the hill.
三排！拿上裝備，我們要上山了
- Just us? - Yeah, just us, lgg.
- 就我們？ - 對，就我們，伊基
All right, Third Platoon, move!
好了，三排，出發！
I tag along?
我跟在後面？
Yeah, you can lead the way if you want. Get a good shot of my face.
你願意在前頭開路也行 給我的臉好好照一張
It's your ass I'm gonna make famous, Hank.
我打算讓你的屁股出名，漢克
Hey, that'll work for me, too.
嘿，那也不壞
Lieutenant,
中尉
if you make it to the top, put this up.
要是你們能上到山頂 就把這個樹起來
Yes, sir.
是，長官
Don't worry, lggy. They never shoot at the first patrol.
別擔心，伊基 他們不會朝第一批出動的人開火
- They don't? - No.
- 他們不會？ - 不會
They want us to go up to the top, signal to the others that it's okay,
他們要等我們上到山頂 發信號讓別人以為沒危險了
then shoot everybody else as they come up the mountain.
然後再掃光其他上山的人
- Really? - Yeah.
- 真的？ - 真的
Unless of course they want to make an example of us
除非他們就是想拿我們開刀
and discourage all the others.
用來嚇唬其他人
I think you're full of crap, you know that, Hank?
我看你是滿嘴胡話，漢克
Really?
真的？
Jesus.
天哪
Thank God that ain't us.
感謝上帝，沒讓我們去
Told you.
我沒說錯吧
Boots, spread them out and put them on a line.
布茨，讓他們散開，組成防線
Set up a perimeter! First Squad!
組成環形防線！一班！
- Hank? Find me a pole. - Yeah.
- 漢克，給我找根旗桿來 - 好的
Let's put this flag up.
咱們把這面旗樹起來
Watch it.
小心
Right over here.
就在這裡
Right here. That's good. That's good. Right here, right here.
就在這裡，好的，好的 就是這裡
Got that end? Hold that steady.
拿住那頭，拿穩了
Lindberg.
林德伯格
- Hey, who's got rope? - Right here.
- 喂，誰有繩子？ - 這兒有
Give me something. Yeah, good.
給我點，好
That work?
這樣行了吧？
Do it, fellas.
來吧，夥計們
Keep it coming.
把它插下去
USMC! USMC!
美國海軍陸戰隊萬歲！
Shit, look at that!
我靠，瞧那兒！
Jeez, look at that.
好傢伙，看啊
Get down! Take cover!
臥倒！注意隱蔽！
Cover with that.30!
用那挺.30機槍掩護！
- Watch it! Twenty yards down, Hank! - You see them?
- 注意！下面二十碼，漢克！ - 你看見他們了？
- I got about 20 yards, left side. - Lindberg, get the flamethrower!
- 大約20碼，左邊 - 林德伯格，拿噴火器來！
- Boots, you see them? - Cover right!
- 布茨，你看見他們了？ - 火力掩護右翼！
- About 20 yards down! Duck one! - You see them?
- 在下面20碼左右！蹲著一個！ - 你看見他們了？
Keep the cover on!
繼續火力掩護！
Second Squad, you see them?
二班，你們看見他們沒有？
Get me some grenades!
給我幾個手榴彈！
I see them!
我看見他們了！
You see them?
你看見他們了？
Right flank, over to the right!
在右翼，右邊！
Cover me, I'm going down!
掩護我，我要下去了！
Careful, lggy.
當心，伊基
Easy.
別急
All clear!
都解決了！
Okay, guys, who wants to be famous?
好了，弟兄們，有誰想出名？
Yes, sir. Right away, sir.
是，長官，馬上就去
- God damn it. Strank! - Sir?
- 我操，斯特蘭克！ - 長官你叫我？
They want a phone line run up to the top of the mountain.
他們要往山頂上拉根電話線
Let me guess, they picked us.
讓我猜猜，他們挑中了我們
Second Platoon, let's go. Get some exercise.
二排，咱們走，去活動活動
Let's go! Get off your ass.
走吧！都給我動起來
Oh, shit!
哦，媽的！
Hope it still works, 'cause you're not getting mine!
希望它還能用 我可不會把我的借給你！
- Get Forrestal! - All right, then.
- 快給福雷斯特爾*拍照！ - 好吧 （* 美國海軍部部長）
I don't know whose idea it was, Mr. Secretary.
我不知道那是誰的點子，部長先生
Well, it was goddamn brilliant. I want that flag, Holland.
真他媽的聰明，我要那面旗，霍蘭* （*霍蘭·史密斯，第五兩棲軍軍長 硫磺島地面戰的總指揮）
Mark my words, raising that son-of-a-bitch
記住我的話吧：樹起那個寶貝
means a Marine Corps for the next 500 years.
就意味著海軍陸戰隊今後五百年的榮耀
I want that flag.
我要那面旗
Yes, sir. I'll make sure no one touches it.
是，長官 我保證沒人能碰它
You can count on me.
您就放心吧
Fuck that. That flag belongs to the men in this battalion.
操他媽的 那面旗是咱們營的
That son-of-a-bitch thinks that our men died taking this ground
那狗娘養的以為 咱們拚死拚活打下這塊地方
so we could hand over our flag to some politician to pin to his wall?
就是為了把咱們的旗子 送給哪個政客當裝飾品？
He's out of his goddamn mind!
他腦子進水了！
Get me that flag, and find another one to replace it.
把那面旗弄下來，再找一面換上去
You've gotta be shitting me.
你準是在拿我開心
Gagnon!
蓋格南！
Get your ass over here.
你給我過來
Hey. Hi, fellas. How's it going?
嗨，夥計們，還好嗎？
Missed a beautiful shot, Joe.
你可錯過好照片了，喬
It's that kind of day.
今天不吉利
- Hey, Mike. - Hell of a view, Lieutenant.
- 嘿，邁克 - 這風景可真夠意思，中尉
Lieutenant!
中尉！
Captain says he wants that flag.
上尉說他要那面旗
He wants this flag?
他要這面旗？
Yes, sir.
是的，長官
- We just put the damn thing up. - Yes, sir.
- 我們剛把這玩意樹起來 - 是的，長官
Some kind of flag shortage?
他的旗子不夠用了？
He wants you to put this one up instead.
他要你用這面旗把它換下來
Hey, Mike.
喂，邁克
Do me a favor and put this up, will you?
幫我個忙，把它樹起來，好嗎？
Yes, sir.
是，長官
All right, let's find a pole.
好吧，咱們找根旗桿
Take the flag down, boys.
把旗子拿下來
Captairs orders.
上尉的命令
You heard him, let's do it.
你們都聽見了，動手吧
There you go.
起
Lordy, she's a heavy one.
老天，這傢伙可真沉
All right, hang on. Put this on.
先停一停，把這個綁上去
One hell of a view, huh?
這風景夠意思吧？
Good view from up here. Yes, I'd say so myself.
對，我也覺得這兒角度不錯
All right.
好
- Not in your way here, am I, Joe? - Nah, I'm fine, thanks.
- 我在這兒不妨礙你吧，喬？ - 不妨礙，謝謝
Hey, Doc, you wanna give us a hand here?
喂，大夫，幫個忙吧？
Oh, Jesus, Bill, here she goes.
哦，比爾，要樹起來了
Ready? Ready?
預備？預備？
Let's go.
來吧
You get it?
你拍到了嗎？
I don't know. I wish I could've seen their faces.
不知道，能拍到他們的臉就好了
Nobody even noticed that second flag going up.
第二面旗樹起來的時候 甚至沒人注意到
Everybody saw that damn picture and made up their own story about it.
大家都是看了那該死的照片 然後自己編了故事
But your dad and the others knew what they had done
可是你爸爸和其他幾個人都知道 哪些事他們做過
and what they had not done.
哪些事沒有做
All your friends dying,
朋友們一個個死去
it's hard not to be called a hero for saving somebody's life.
靠救人成為英雄無可厚非
But for putting up a pole?
可是靠插根旗桿當英雄是怎麼回事？
You gotta be kidding.
你準是在開玩笑
Hey! It took a lot of talented folks a long time to make that thing.
嘿！這東西可是一大幫能工巧匠 費了好大功夫才做出來的
Just wait till tonight when it's lit properly
只要等到今晚，用燈光這麼一照
and there's thousands of cheering people in the stands.
再讓幾萬人在看台上這麼一喊
It's gonna look a lot better.
那就會美多了
So, stadium lights come down,
運動場的燈從上往下照
spotlight comes up and you get your cue.
聚光燈從下往上照 你們就拿著旗桿
You charge up this thing with the flag, you plant it at the top.
你們帶著旗子衝上這假山 然後把它插在頂上
You smile, you wave. You know the drill.
你們微笑、揮手 你們都知道該怎麼做
You want us to plant the flag on a pile of papier-mache.
你要我們在一堆紙板上插旗
Hey, that's show biz.
嘿，那是表演
And try and stand how you stood the first time you planted it.
你們要按當初插旗時候的位置站
Just, you know, pretend the other three guys are with you.
就當那三個人也和你們在一起
The dead guys.
死掉的人
Yeah. Yeah.
對，對
Okay, not a problem.
好吧，沒問題
Good.
很好
But where do we imagine Hank is standing?
可是我們該怎麼想像漢克站的位置？
Sorry?
什麼意思？
Well, seeing that he wasrt there,
既然我們知道他不在場
it'll be kind of hard for us to leave a space for him.
要讓我們給他留個位置就有點困難
I think you know exactly where he was. You pointed him out to his mother.
我想你知道他在什麼位置 你指給他媽媽看過
This is bullshit.
這是狗屁
I planted that damn thing once, and I'm not doing it again.
我已經插過一回那玩意 不想再插第二回了
- Hayes! - Oh, for Christ's sake.
- 海耶斯！ - 哦，看在基督份上
Hayes. Hayes, get your ass back here or you're going on report.
海耶斯，海耶斯你給我回來 要不然我就向上面告你
Hayes!
海耶斯！
You wanna do your damn job?
你到底想不想幹活？
Let go of me! Let go of me!
放開我！放開我！
Come on!
快放開！
He's with me!
我們是一起的！
- Back off! - Sir, he's with me. Okay? He's with me.
- 別過來！ - 警官，我們是一起的
Ira, put the goddamn chair down!
艾拉，快把椅子放下！
- Put the chair down, son! - Put the chair down, Ira!
- 把椅子放下，小伙子！ - 把椅子放下，艾拉！
Tell them drop their sticks!
叫他們先把棍子扔了！
Ira, they're cops, they're supposed to have nightsticks.
艾拉，他們是警察 當然可以拿警棍
You're not supposed to be in the street swinging a chair.
你在街上掄椅子就不對了
- Calm down, son. - Sir, turn around, please.
- 冷靜點，小伙子 - 警官，請你朝後邊看
That poster right there? The one on the end, that's him.
看見那張海報沒？ 最左邊的人，就是他
- That's him? - Yes, sir. You read the papers?
- 那是他？ - 是的，警官，你看報嗎？
Christ.
老天
We got another fucking hero. Get him out of here.
又是一個他媽的英雄 你帶他走吧
- Can you do that? - Yes, sir.
- 你能辦到嗎？ - 可以
Put the goddamn chair down. And let's go.
快把椅子放下，咱們走
Did you start this?
是你挑起來的嗎？
He didn't serve me!
他不肯接待我！
I don't make the rules. We don't serve Indians.
規矩不是我訂的 我們店不接待印第安人
He needs to go sleep it off.
他該去睡一覺，把這事忘掉
Soldier Field.
去軍人廣場
You hear that?
你聽見嗎？
What the hell is that?
到底是什麼聲音？
I can't figure it out.
我想不出
Keep an eye out.
注意找找
It sounds like it's coming from up there.
好像是從上面傳來的
They're using grenades.
是手榴彈的聲音
They're killing themselves.
他們自殺了
Ira, let's go.
艾拉，咱們走
Come on.
快點
Let's go, Ira. Come on.
咱們走，艾拉，快點
Thank God. Jesus. Look at you, Chief.
感謝上帝，瞧你那樣，酋長
You found him.
你找到他了
Holy shit. You would have to pick today.
見鬼，你準是故意挑在今天搗亂
Vandegrift is here with enough brass to start a fucking band.
范德格裡夫特*來了，還帶著一群大官 將星多得可以開舖子了 （*海軍陸戰隊總司令）
Come on, let's go. Can you walk?
快點，咱們走，你能走路嗎？
- Yes, sir. - By yourself?
- 是的，長官 - 你一個人能行？
All right, look. I don't care if you have to carry him
好吧，你們把他抬過去也行
get him to the top, plant that flag, and don't fucking fall off.
只要讓他上去，插好旗，別摔下來就行
Get him in his stuff. I'll stall these guys for as long as I can. Hurry up.
給他換好衣服，我會盡量拖住 那些人的，快去
Jesus Christ.
上帝啊
And now, the heroes of lwo Jima!
現在，讓我們歡迎硫磺島的英雄們！
Cover!
隱蔽！
Harlon!
哈龍！
Harlon! Get your fire team up in that position!
哈龍！帶火力組搶佔那個位置！
O'Hare!
奧海爾！
First Fire Team!
第一火力組！
Work around!
繞過去！
BAR, you, on the side of the ridge!
你，自動步槍手，去山脊那邊！
Covering fire, boys, go, go, go!
火力掩護，弟兄們，打，打！
Jackson, work your team around to the left!
傑克遜，讓你的小組繞到左邊去！
Cover!
掩護！
Left flank! Left flank!
左翼！左翼！
Franklin, Gust, go check it out!
富蘭克林，戈斯特，去看看！
Hustle up, boys!
衝上去，弟兄們！
We got them!
幹掉他們了！
Clear!
解決了！
One hell of an experience.
真是糟透了
Move out!
前進！
Cease fire! They're my men! You're targeting our men!
停止射擊！那是我的兵！ 你們在打自己人！
You're targeting our...
你們在打自己……
Get me another radio!
再拿個步話機來！
Sergeant? Sergeant!
中士？中士！
Mike!
邁克！
Mike, Mike, Mike.
邁克，邁克
Mike? Mike.
邁克？邁克
Hey, where's Doc?
大夫在哪兒？
Corpsman!
看護兵！
Oh, shit.
糟了
How's his breathing? Harlon, move, buddy.
他呼吸怎樣？ 哈龍，你讓一讓
Hey, Mike. Mike, Mike, can you hear us?
邁克，邁克，能聽見我們嗎？
It's okay.
不要緊的
Come on, Mike.
挺住，邁克
Mike? Mike, can you hear us?
邁克？邁克，能聽見我們嗎？
All right, let's go!
好了，咱們走！
Move out!
前進！
I'm gonna get a stretcher.
我去找副擔架
Let's take him down, move him off the beach.
咱們把他抬到海灘上去
Ladies and gentlemen, the heroes of lwo Jima!
女士們，先生們 硫磺島的英雄們來了！
Corpsman!
看護兵！
Hank!
漢克！
Doc, they killed me.
大夫，他們打死我了
Harlon!
哈龍！
Doc,
大夫
they killed me.
他們打死我了
Come on, Harlon. Harlon, stay with me.
挺住，哈龍，哈龍，別丟下我
Franklin!
富蘭克林！
I'm fine, Ira.
我沒事，艾拉
Corpsman!
看護兵！
- Where'd he go? - Who?
- 他去哪兒了？ - 誰？
The guy who was right here, Ignatowski. Where did he go?
在這裡的人，伊格納托斯基 他去哪兒了？
- I think you jumped in the wrong hole. - I didn't jump in the wrong hole!
- 我看你是進錯散兵坑了 - 我沒進錯！
He was right here, now where the hell is he?
剛才他還在這兒的 他到底去哪兒了？
Lggy!
伊基！
You shut up. You want every Jap on the island shooting at us?
別叫了，你想讓島上的鬼子 都朝我們這兒打嗎？
Lggy!
伊基！
Does it open?
下面是空的？
Lggy, are you down there?
伊基，你在裡面嗎？
Lggy!
伊基！
Can't tell who it is, but he's one of ours.
認不出是誰，不過肯定是我們的人
I had to go outside to throw up.
我實在忍不住，只好出來吐
Look what they did to the poor son-of-a-bitch.
你去瞧瞧他們對那個倒霉蛋幹了什麼
You okay, Chief?
你不要緊吧，酋長？
Just let it go.
吐了就好
If that doesn't pry open their wallets, nothing will.
要是這還不能讓他們掏錢 那就沒法子了
Jesus Christ, he's drunk.
老天，他醉了
Goddamn Indians.
他媽的印第安佬
Come on, Chief. Let's get you home.
來吧，酋長，咱們回家去
That's not what I hear. I called around, I'm not stupid.
我聽到的不是這樣 我已經打聽過了，我也不笨
He's been drunk since he started this damn tour,
自從巡講開始，他就一直在酗酒
making a spectacle of himself.
丟人現眼
Just about choked that poor woman at the reception, blubbering.
在歡迎會上抱著可憐的老太太 又哭又鬧，差點沒把人家悶死
Jesus Christ, you're supposed to be watching these men.
老天，你應該管好他們的
Yes, sir.
是，長官
Well, he's making us look like regular asses.
他讓我們像傻瓜一樣
Well, with all due respect, sir,
恕我冒犯，長官
he never wanted to come on this trip in the first place.
他從一開始就不想參加巡講
We had to pull him, kicking and screaming, off that boat.
他在船上又踢又叫 我們是把他硬拉下來的
He wants to be with his unit.
他想留在自己的部隊裡
What unit? They're all fucking dead.
什麼部隊？他的部隊都翹辮子了
This is how he honors those men? By drinking and throwing up, and...
他就是這麼給部隊爭光的？ 喝了吐，吐了喝……
You know what? He wants it, great, we'll send him back.
好啊，既然他想回去 我們就送他回去
Get him packed and on a train today. He's an embarrassment to the uniform.
讓他收拾收拾，今天就上火車 他玷污了那身軍裝
Yes, sir.
是，長官
I'll do it.
我來辦
Yeah, no, that's... That's good. That's what I want.
是啊，那樣…… 那樣也好，我也希望這樣
I know it's a good thing,
我知道這是好事
raising the money and that, 'cause we need it.
我們來籌款，是因為我們需要錢
But,
可是
I can't take them calling me a hero.
他們叫我英雄，我受不了
All I did was try not to get shot.
我做過的事就是拚命躲子彈
Some of the things I saw done,
我看到的一些事
things I did,
還有我自己做的一些事
they werert things to be proud of, you know?
都不值得驕傲
Mike...
邁克……
Mike was a hero.
邁克才是英雄
You ever meet him?
你見過他嗎？
No.
沒有
Best Marine I ever met.
我見過的最好的陸戰隊員
You know, Chief, I think if Mike was sitting here instead of you
知道嗎，酋長，我覺得 要是邁克代替你坐在這裡
he'd be saying the same thing about himself,
他也會說一樣的話
not being a hero.
說自己不是英雄
Maybe.
也許吧
He was a good guy.
他是個好人
But I think that he would be ashamed of me,
可我覺得，要是他看見我這個樣子
seeing me the way I am.
他會感到羞恥的
Think I could see my ma before they ship me off?
你看，我臨走前能不能見我媽媽？
Think they'd do that? See my ma?
你看他們會同意嗎？讓我見媽媽？
I'm sorry, Ira.
很抱歉，艾拉
We got stories now to tell our kids, I guess.
這麼一來我們可有故事講給孩子聽了
Keep your head down.
小心點
All aboard.
都上車
Good luck, Chief.
祝你好運，酋長
I think I saw him once after that.
我覺得我後來還見過他一回
It was maybe six or seven years after the war.
大概是在戰後六七年的樣子
I was working as a salesman, doing a lot of driving.
我當了推銷員，經常開車跑業務
I was driving west across Texas.
有一次我開車向西橫穿德克薩斯
I was just trying to get where I was going so I could get home.
我只想早點去目的地 辦完事就回家
And I saw this guy hitchhiking on the side of the road.
我在路上看見一個想搭便車的人
And, for a second, I thought it might've been him.
有那麼一會兒 我覺得那可能就是他
I always regret that I didn't stop, but I was in a hurry.
我一直後悔沒有停車 當時我太著急了
And he was an Indian.
他是個印第安人
We always told the press that Ira insisted
我們一直對新聞界說
that he was going back to fight with his unit
艾拉堅持要回去和戰友並肩作戰
which was at least partially true, but
這話至少一半是真的
that isn't what got the headlines.
可是報紙上卻不是這麼說的
We're engaged.
我們訂婚了
Excuse me a minute, darling.
等我一下，親愛的
- Hey, Doc? - Yeah?
- 嘿，大夫 - 嗯？
- Got a minute? - Yeah.
- 有空嗎？ - 有
I'll see you at the car.
我在車上等你
- You hear I'm getting married? - I did, Rene. That's great.
- 你知道我要結婚了吧？ - 知道，雷尼，太好了
Yeah, it's something she wants. She waited for me all this time.
是她提出來的，她一直在等我
She's not used to all this, but she's a good girl.
她還不習慣這一切 不過她是個好姑娘
I'm sure you'll be very happy.
你們肯定會很美滿
So, I was wondering if you'd be my best man.
我想知道，你願不願意當我的儐相
Me?
我？
Don't you have somebody at home, a buddy, you'd rather ask?
你不想找老家的朋友嗎？
Well, I didn't really make many.
其實，我的朋友不多
The ones who didn't go, it's... Well, it's hard to even talk to them.
那些沒參軍的人…… 我甚至很難和他們搭上話
You know?
你明白嗎？
Yeah, I know.
我明白
I'd be proud to.
我很樂意
Thank you.
謝謝
I better go drag her away from them before she announces
我最好快點把她拉走
I'm gonna be president of General Motors or something.
省得她宣佈我要當通用汽車的總裁
All right.
好
- Congratulations. - Thank you so much. Thank you.
- 恭喜你 - 太謝謝了
Rene, you're a lucky man.
雷尼，你可真走運
- Big smile, Mrs. Gagnon! - Say cheese!
- 笑一個，雷尼太太！ - 說「茄子」！
I couldn't complain because the press loved them,
我不能抱怨，因為新聞界喜歡他們
so they wrote more articles and people bought more bonds.
這樣他們就有更多報道可寫 大家也就會買更多債券
The tour went on with just Rene and your dad.
巡講繼續，只剩下雷尼和你爸爸
And the true heroes are the men who didn't make it home from lwo Jima,
真正的英雄是沒能從硫磺島回家的人
the men who died at lwo Jima and in other campaigns.
是那些在硫磺島和其他戰役中犧牲的人
We ask that you honor the memory of those men
請你們用購買戰爭債券的方式緬懷英烈
by buying the war bonds and helping us to win this war.
幫助我們打贏這場戰爭
Thank you.
謝謝
City after city, I thought the damn thing'd never end.
一個城接著一個城 我以為這事會沒完沒了
And this rumor kept going around that the photograph had been staged.
這時候流言四起，說那張照片是擺拍的
I remember your dad telling them
我記得你爸爸對他們說
that he wished he'd known he was having his picture taken
要是他知道當時有人在拍照就好了
because he would've ducked the hell out of it.
那樣的話他準會躲起來
Whose idea was it? Who wanted to stage the thing?
這是誰的主意？ 誰想到要擺拍這張照片？
Come on, it was you?
是你嗎？
Was there truth to the rumor that that picture was staged, Doc?
有傳言說那張照片是擺拍的 這是真的嗎？
- Come on! Doc? - Can you answer that?
- 你說話呀，大夫！ - 你能回答嗎？
I remember when your dad got shot. All hell was busting loose.
我記得你爸爸中彈的時候 好像整個地獄的雷火都冒了出來
People back home saw that picture
後方的人看到那張照片
and thought it was over when we took Suribachi.
以為我們佔領折缽山時 戰鬥就結束了
We wished.
真是那樣就好了
Anyways, we're pinned down.
其實我們被壓得動彈不得
Mortars, shells, machine guns.
迫擊炮、大炮、機槍
Fire coming from every which direction, right?
從四面八方打過來
And we hear somebody call, "Corpsman down."
我們聽見有人喊：「看護兵中彈了」
Corpsman down!
看護兵中彈了！
Blood was spurting out of his throat, and Doc was doing everything he could.
血從他的喉嚨裡直標出來 大夫盡了一切努力
And the Corpsman looks up at him
那個看護兵盯著他看
and he knows what this means, to be shot in the neck.
他知道脖子中彈的後果
He knows he's dying, you can see that.
我看得出來，他知道自己快死了
But still
可是看他的眼神
in his eyes, he's pleading with Doc to save his life.
他一直在求大夫救他的命
And Doc can't.
可是大夫做不到
- You okay, Doc? - Yeah, I'm fine.
- 你不要緊吧，大夫？ - 我沒事
- Yeah, you look fine. - I'm okay.
- 我看你問題不大
Keep down, all right? I'm gonna go get a stretcher.
趴著別動好嗎？ 我去找副擔架來
Okay.
好的
Corpsman. Corpsman!
看護兵，看護兵！
For God sake, Corpsman!
看在上帝份上，看護兵！
Corpsman?
看護兵？
Corpsman.
看護兵
Incoming!
炮彈來了！
Let me see.
讓我看看
It's not that bad. You're gonna be okay. All right?
不是太糟，你會好的，明白嗎？
Just stay with me. Look at me.
你挺住，看著我
Took us a half-hour to find your dad. He could've bled to death.
我們費了半小時才找到你爸爸 他差點流血過多死掉
Coming down.
放下來
Thanks.
謝謝
Vets'll tell you about being hit but not wanting to leave their buddies.
老兵們會對你說 他們雖然中彈，卻不願拋棄戰友
Usually, they're lying.
多數時候，他們是在撒謊
You'll take any excuse to get out of there.
你會利用一切借口來離開戰場
But it happens.
但確實有例外
You get the feeling you're letting them down.
那種人總覺得自己辜負了他們
I could see that in your dad's face.
我從你爸爸的表情上看得出來
He wanted to go, he'd seen enough.
他想走，他已經受夠了
But he didn't want to leave us.
可是他不願拋下我們
Now, he was a hell of a good man, your dad.
你爸爸真是菩薩心腸
Yeah.
是啊
While we were sitting there on the beach, we heard this great roar.
正當我們坐在海灘上的時候 聽見一陣巨響
And we looked up.
我們抬頭一看
That was the first of thousands of landings on lwo.
那是第一架在硫磺島著陸的飛機 以後又有上萬架
- Look at that. - Yeah.
- 看哪 - 嗯
How about that.
還不錯吧
I'm gonna head back, all right?
我會回來的
Good luck.
祝你好運
That island saved a lot of lives.
那個島救了很多人的命
A lot of lives.
很多人的命
I don't know what else to tell you.
我不知道還有什麼可說的
After the bond tour my dad finally got his operation.
巡講結束以後，我爸爸終於做了手術
By the time he got home the war was over.
等他回家時，戰爭已經結束了
First thing he did was ask my mom to marry him.
他做的第一件事就是求我媽媽嫁給他
Ira tried to get on with his life and put it all behind him.
艾拉想接著過自己的生活 把所有事都忘掉
Thank you for having me here today.
謝謝你們今天請我來
It's an honor to be in front of such a strong people.
給你們這些好漢作報告是我的榮幸
Because of the war
通過這場戰爭
white men will understand Indians a lot better.
白人會更好地理解印第安人
And it's going to be a better world.
我們的處境也會更好
But life had other plans for him.
但是人生總難如意
You're... You're him, aren't you?
你是……你是那個人吧？
You're the hero, right?
你是那個英雄，對嗎？
Great. All right, kids, go get your picture taken.
太好了，來吧，孩子們 去拍照吧
Oh, that's great. That's great.
太好了，太好了
All right, now say cheese.
好，說「茄子」
Cheese!
茄子！
That's great! Okay. Hey, thanks a lot. Thanks.
太好了 謝謝，太謝謝了
- Come on. - That's a hero, kids.
- 走吧 - 那可是英雄啊，孩子們
Hero, lift this basket, will you? It's too heavy for me.
英雄，幫我抬抬這個籃子好嗎？ 我搬不動啊
Rene tried to take advantage of those offers he'd received on the bond tour.
雷尼想接受他在債券巡講時 接到的聘用邀請
Yes. G-A-G-N-O-N.
是的，G-A-G-N-O-N
Right. Pronounced Rene. Rene, yes.
對，發音是「雷尼」，雷尼
- Okay, I actually called last week. - Yes. Okay, yes. Mr. Gagnon.
- 其實我上禮拜就打過電話了 - 好的，好的，蓋格南先生
I gave Mr. Tennack your message. I'm sure he'll call you.
我已經轉告泰納克先生了 他肯定會給你回電的
Okay. All right.
好吧
Thank you.
謝謝
But he was yesterday's hero.
但他已經是過氣英雄了
He even applied for a job at the local police station.
他甚至到當地警察局找過工作
They said he wasrt qualified.
他們說他不夠資格
After working the factory with Pauline he tried a few things
和波琳一起在工廠幹過一陣後 他試過很多工作
but spent the rest of his life as a janitor.
但是他的下半輩子都在做看門人
But Ira...
而艾拉……
Ira! You got a visitor.
艾拉！有人來看你
Ira always made the news.
艾拉總是能上新聞
I could never find out why he did it, but one day Ira just took off.
有一天艾拉出走了 至於他為什麼要走，我一直沒明白
He walked and hitched over 1,300 miles
他靠步行和搭便車走了1300多英里
from Arizona to Texas.
從亞利桑那到德克薩斯
He found Harlon Block's father working his field.
艾拉找到了哈龍·布洛克的父親 他正在田里幹活
His wife, Belle, had left him soon after they discovered Harlon died.
他妻子蓓爾得知哈龍犧牲的消息 就和他離婚了
She never forgave him for letting her son go off to war.
她永遠不能原諒他讓兒子上戰場
And Ira told him the truth,
艾拉把真相告訴了他
that it had been his son who raised the flag with them,
和他們一起插旗的是他兒子
his son in the photograph.
他兒子就在照片上
And then he just turned and walked away.
說完他就轉身離開
Though the flag-raising meant nothing to him,
雖然插旗的事對他毫無意義
he somehow knew it would mean everything to them.
但是他知道那對他們意義非凡
Thanks for calling.
謝謝你來電話
Just as Belle knew all along.
果然和蓓爾想的一樣
The press soon found out
新聞界很快也發現了
and called Hank's mom with the news that it wasrt her son after all.
他們告訴漢克的媽媽 他兒子根本不在照片上
The last time they all saw each other
他們最後一次碰頭
was at the unveiling of the Marine Corps War Memorial.
是在海軍陸戰隊戰爭紀念碑的揭幕式上
And even though he planted the first flag above lwo Jima,
雖然硫磺島的第一面旗是漢克插的
Hank's mother and father werert invited.
漢克的父母卻沒有被邀請出席
Ira.
艾拉
It's good to see you, Ira.
見到你很高興，艾拉
Hell of a statue.
這雕像真夠意思
It wasrt long after that that they found Ira.
不久以後人們發現了埃拉的屍體
The papers said he died of exposure. There was no autopsy.
報上說他死於風餐露宿 警方沒有驗屍
It was about that same time
差不多也是在這時候
when my father got in his car early one morning
有天早上我爸爸鑽進汽車
telling my mom he had something to do.
對我媽媽說他有事要辦
He drove to a town on the other side of Wisconsin where lggy's mom lived.
他去了威斯康星另一頭的小鎮 那裡住著伊基的媽媽
Ever since she heard the news about her son
自從得到兒子的死訊
she'd been trying to find out how he died, and no one would tell her.
她就想知道他是怎麼死的 可是沒人願意告訴她
I never found out what he told her,
我一直沒弄清爸爸是怎麼對她說的
but I can pretty much guarantee it wasrt the truth.
但是我有十足把握相信，他沒有說實話
My mother would ask him what was troubling him.
我媽媽曾問，到底是什麼事讓他煩惱
He would never say.
但他從來不肯說
And every year, as it got close to Memorial Day,
每年臨近陣亡將士紀念日
the reporters would start calling asking to interview my father.
就有記者打來電話，請求採訪我爸爸
No, I'm sorry. He's fishing in Canada.
不好意思，他去加拿大釣魚了
We were always instructed to say the same thing.
他總是讓我們用同一番話來搪塞
Okay. Thanks.
好的，謝謝
When Mr. McCandless retired,
麥坎得利斯先生退休時
my father bought the funeral home where he'd worked since coming home.
我爸爸買下了他的殯儀館 復員以後他一直在裡面工作
He spent the rest of his life running the business and raising his family.
他把下半輩子都用來經營業務 養家餬口
He never spoke about the war or about the flag-raising,
他從沒談起戰爭和插旗的事
never told us anything.
對我們隻字不提
The first time I heard any of these stories was after he died.
我第一次聽說這些事是在他去世後
Where is he? Oh, God.
他在哪兒？上帝
He's not here, Dad.
他不在這，爸爸
He died.
他死了
Who? Who died?
誰？誰死了？
Lggy.
伊基
Christ, poor lggy.
天哪，可憐的伊基
I hadrt thought of him for years.
我有好多年沒想起他了
How do you know about lggy?
你怎麼知道伊基的？
You were calling for him, when you collapsed.
你病倒的時候就在喊他
I wasrt looking for lggy.
我不是在找伊基
I was looking for you.
我是在找你
I wanted to...
我想……
I wanted to tell you I'm sorry I wasrt a better father.
我想告訴你 我這個爸爸本可以做得更好的
Talked to you more.
本該多和你談談心
I just...
我只想……
I'm sorry.
對不起
Sorry?
對不起？
You were the best father a man could have.
你是天底下最好的爸爸
Did I ever tell you they took us swimming?
我有沒有和你說過 他們讓我們游泳的事？
No, Dad.
沒有，爸爸
After we planted the flag, we came down off the mountain
我們插完旗後，下了山
and they let us swim.
他們允許我們游泳
It was the funniest thing.
真是太好玩了
All this fighting
周圍都在戰鬥
and we were jumping around in the water like kids.
我們卻像孩子一樣蹦到水裡
That's the way I remember lggy now.
關於伊基，我現在就只記得這個
I finally came to the conclusion that maybe he was right.
最後我得出結論，也許他是對的
Maybe there's no such thing as heroes.
也許這世上並沒有英雄
Maybe there are just people like my dad.
只有我爸爸這樣的普通人
I finally came to understand
最後我終於明白
why they were so uncomfortable being called heroes.
為什麼英雄的稱號 會讓他們這麼不自在
Heroes are something we create, something we need.
英雄都是我們塑造出來的 我們需要英雄
It's a way for us to understand what is almost incomprehensible,
因為不這麼做我們就理解不了
how people could sacrifice so much for us.
為什麼有人可以為我們流血犧牲
But for my dad and these men,
但是對我爸爸和這些人來說
the risks they took, the wounds they suffered,
他們出生入死，流血犧牲
they did that for their buddies.
都是為了他們的戰友
They may have fought for their country, but they died for their friends.
他們也許曾為祖國而戰 但他們是為戰友而死
For the man in front, for the man beside them.
為了他們身前和身邊的人
And if we wish to truly honor these men,
如果我們真要緬懷這些人
we should remember them the way they really were,
就應該記住他們真實的一面
the way my dad remembered them.
我爸爸記住的那一面
Come on, Doc!
快過來，大夫！